<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pinterest on BenHall.ca</title><link>https://benhall.ca/tags/pinterest/</link><description>Recent content in Pinterest on BenHall.ca</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benhall.ca/tags/pinterest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pinterest for Business and All in One SEO Pack</title><link>https://benhall.ca/post/2013-11-11-pinterest-for-business-and-all-in-one-seo-pack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://benhall.ca/post/2013-11-11-pinterest-for-business-and-all-in-one-seo-pack/</guid><description>&lt;p>The two main steps are to create a Pinterest for Businsess account, and then confirm your website.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="get-set-up-on-pinterest-for-business">Get Set up on Pinterest for Business
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to &lt;a class="link" href="http://business.pinterest.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Pinterest for Business&lt;/a> and click on &amp;ldquo;Join as a Business&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fill out the &amp;ldquo;Create a Business Account&amp;rdquo; form:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I selected &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo; as the business type;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You need to choose an email address that doesn&amp;rsquo;t already have an account with Pinterest. I ended up using my gmail account so I used the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;generate&amp;rdquo; a new email address. Meaning, if my email address at gmail.com was &lt;code>foo@gmail.com&lt;/code>, I used &lt;code>foo+sailinghall@gmail.com&lt;/code>. Pinterest recognized it as a separate email address, but gmail directs emails to &lt;code>foo+sailinghall@gmail.com&lt;/code> to the regular &lt;code>foo@gmail.com&lt;/code> address.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I filled in username, business name, and website all as expected, and left the rest of the fields alone.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to your email account and confirm your email address following the directions in the email.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="confirm-your-website">Confirm Your Website
&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Back at Pinterest, click on your account name in the upper right, and select Settings from the menu.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on Edit Profile.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on Verify Website (the name of the website should already have been filled in from your &amp;ldquo;Create a Business Account&amp;rdquo; page earlier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on Verify with a meta tag.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy the value in the content attribute to your clipboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In other tab, log in to your WordPress admin account. From the dashboard menu on the left select &amp;ldquo;All in One SEO Pack&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;General Settings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to &amp;ldquo;Pinterest Site Verification&amp;rdquo; under &amp;ldquo;Webmaster Verification&amp;rdquo; and paste the code that you copied from Pinterest.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scroll down to the bottom and click &amp;ldquo;Update Options&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After the WordPress settings are saved, go back to your Pinterest tab, and click &amp;ldquo;Complete Verification&amp;rdquo;. Interestingly, there&amp;rsquo;s no feedback if this is successful, but if you click &amp;ldquo;Complete Verification&amp;rdquo; a second time, it will tell you that the site has already been verified. Click on the X to dismiss the Verify Your Website dialog.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>While saving my &amp;ldquo;Profile&amp;rdquo;, I had to fix the website name to include &amp;ldquo;http://&amp;rdquo; in front of the website name. The &amp;ldquo;Create a Business Account&amp;rsquo; page had stripped the http:// that I originally added.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Back on the Pinterest Account Settings page, there are a lot of options to associate your Pinterest account with many other social networks. I suppose this makes sense, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t done it myself. It reminds me to think about my social networking strategy though.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>